Emilio Gonzalez

Senior Full Stack Software Engineer

emilio.gonzalez.dev@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/emilgonz/ • San Antonio, TX

Summary

A senior Full-Stack Developer with 8 years of strong experience in modern web technologies and various industry expertise, with strong proficiency in technologies such as JavaScript, Node.js, React, Angular, Django, AWS I'm passionate about solving complex problems across projects and focus on ensuring the best quality and fast delivery of time

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 $Languages: JavaScript \cdot TypeScript \cdot Python \cdot Java \cdot GraphQL \cdot SQL \cdot HTML/CSS$

Frameworks: React · Redux · Angular · Node.js · Django · FastAPI · Spring Boot · Express.js

DBMS: MySQL · MongoDB · PostgreSQL · DynamoDB

Tools & Platforms: Git/GitHub · Terraform · Jenkins · Docker · Kubernetes · AWS · Azure

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Dynamic Dashboard

Developed a dynamic dashboard with real-time data visualization, enhancing user insights

Performance Optimization

Optimized performance for both front-end and backend techniques that reduced page load times by 50%

Fast Delivery of projects

Ensured fast delivery of projects, via strong communication with clients and team members

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The Trade Desk

Ventura, CA

Senior Full Stack Developer

03/2022 - 04/2024

Delivered all projects in fast time, meeting all the requirements from clients with excellent communication skills

- Built interactive ad creatives, landing pages, and multimedia content in web using React, Next.js, TailwindCSS, with GraphOL
- Developed advertising campaign management dashboard using Angular 16, NgRx, utilizing Angular CLI and refactored legacy Angular JS codebase to Angular 16 following best migration principles
- Developed RESTful APIs and multiple backend microservices using Node.js, Express.js, Python, Django, with Amazon EC2,
 S3, API Gateway integrated RESTful APIs into React frontend
- Integrated Prisma seamlessly with GraphQL to create flexible and performant APIs, allowing for precise data retrieval and manipulation
- Managed database interactions and data modeling for Python backend applications, utilizing PostgreSQL and MongoDB databases and leveraged database indexing, and query optimization
- Integrated deep neural networks and machine learning algorithms with web applications based in Python, Django, and PostgreSQL
- · Developed shell scripting and Python programs to automate the data flow on day-to-day tasks
- Used Technologies for SSR implementation (React with Next.js, Angular with Angular Universal)
- · Took part in all steps of the agile SDLC(Software Development Life Cycle) utilizing Jira and Confluence
- · Actively participated in peer code reviews as a reviewer gaining insights into different coding styles, techniques

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Walmart, Inc Hoboken, NJ

Full Stack FE Developer 05/2020 - 02/2022

Contributed to the company's suite of software solutions, working on 70% frontend, 30% backend, and ensured fast performance

- Developed UI/UX for financial dashboard based on React, D3.js and Material UI for cone of clients and integrated API
- Created multiple SEO-friendly SaaS platforms written in React frontend and Node.js backend, collaborating with marketing and development teams
- Responsible for building all web-based applications written in Node, JavaScript, Typescript, React, Material UI and employed code instrumentation and profiling tools to analyze runtime behavior
- Built the back end in Node.js as an AWS Lambda microservice, saving the clients from spending on upfront costs related to hosting
- Conducted test-driven development (TDD) practices, writing unit tests and A/B tests with Jest, Cypress, React Testing
 Library
- · Utilized Redux and React hooks for managing component and application-level states for large-scale web applications
- · Migrated a searching mechanism to utilize Elasticsearch's superior full-text search functionality
- Created the data model and implemented it on MySQL (AWS RDS) using a denormalized design, improving querying performance by 4x

Solvelt Lafayette, LA

Full Stack Developer 10/2016 - 05/2020

Started with new technologies, such as React, Node.js, Java, Spring Boot, and gained expertise in industry trends and business

- Designed, implemented and maintained SEO-friendly and responsive web applications with HTML/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React and integrate them into CMS platform
- Implemented responsive and mobile-first design strategies in React web applications to ensure seamless user experiences across various devices and screen sizes
- Responsible for full-stack development of enterprise-grade web applications for businesses using React, Node.js,
 MongoDB, and other backend systems using Java, Spring Boot, Spring Security
- Built multiple robust e-commerce backend services using Java, Spring Boot, Hibernate leveraging Core Java technologies, such as concurrency, I/O, multithreading and others
- · Engineered Spring Boot microservices, for handling large-scale data integrating third-party services and REST APIs
- Optimized frontend performance by leveraging techniques such as code splitting, lazy loading, and caching to minimize load times
- Actively participated in Agile development methodologies, including sprint planning, stand-ups, and retrospectives, to deliver high-quality software on time
- · Integrated external data sources, such as weather APIs, Google APIs and geolocation services, into mobile applications

Education

Marquette University
Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

Milwaukee, WI

2012 - 2016